web-savvy-marketing.com 2019-04-05

# Privacy Policy

## **Who We Are**

Our website address is: https://www.web-savvy-marketing.com.

## **Data We Collect and Why We Collect It**

Web Savvy Marketing collects and uses information through this website or our online communications (such as email lists) for the purposes set forth within this policy. 

We collect several types of information about you. We may collect this information either directly when you provide it to us or automatically as you navigate through our website.

### **Information You Choose to Provide**

We collect the information you choose to provide to us when you sign up, correspond with us, or interact with our website.

Information collected includes personal information provided in contact inquiries, purchases, or when an individual subscribes to our email list. We require your email address at a minimum, however, in some cases we also ask for additional information to help us better service you and fulfill your request. We do not collect any personal information that you do not expressly provide.

#### **Comments**

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

#### **Contact or Registration Forms**

When you register for an event such as a webinar, we will collect your name and e-mail address as well as a variety of other information that may be pertinent to the type of contact or registration. We will email you about the event or respond to your comment as is applicable.

#### **Opt-in to hear from us**

When you opt into our newsletter and mailing list, we collect your name and e-mail address. We use a third-party service to collect your information and distribute the newsletter: Drip.

### **Information We Collect Automatically**

#### **Cookies**

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.

If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.

#### **Google Analytics**

When someone visits our website we use Google Analytics to collect standard Internet usage information and details of visitor behavior patterns. We do this to learn more about how our website is working, how many visitors we have and what is being accessed and useful to our visitors. This information is only processed in a way which does not identify anyone. We do not make any attempt to find out the identities of those visiting our website.

This information is collected and stored by Google and not on our website. The information collected does not include your email, name, account information, or billing information. It includes such information as:

  * Your IP address or proxy server IP address
  * Basic domain information
  * Your Internet service provider
  * Date and time of your visit to our website
  * Length of time on our website
  * Pages you have accessed
  * Website which referred you to us
  * Operating system your computer uses

## **Additional Information**

### **Embedded content from other websites**

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

### **How Long We Retain Your Data**

Generally, all information is stored indefinitely unless you request to remove it.

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.

We do not expire the Google Analytics data pertaining to your visit to our website.

### **What Rights You Have Over Your Data**

If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

### **Where We Send Your Data**

Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service.

We use a third-party provider, Drip, to deliver our newsletter. We gather statistics around email opening and clicks using industry standard technologies to help us monitor and improve our e-newsletter. For more information, please see [Drip’s](https://www.drip.com/privacy) privacy notice.

When you make a purchase on our website certain types of sensitive information, such as financial information, may be collected. We do not receive or retain copies of this information on our server. We redirect visitors to a secure server to complete these transactions and all data is both collected and stored by these processors. Current payment gateways in use are maintained by PayPal and Stripe. For more information, please see [PayPal’s](https://www.paypal.com/us/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full) and[ Stripe’s](https://stripe.com/us/privacy) privacy notices.

We will not sell, rent, or share your personal information to any third party for marketing purposes without your consent.

### **How We Protect Your Data**

The security of your personal information is important to us.

  * Your information is sent over an authenticated and encrypted connection using the Secure Socket Layer (SSL).
  * We communicate with third-party partners (as identified in this Privacy Policy) via SSL.
  * We use firewalls, limit login attempts, and host with a provider who actively monitors security and intrusions on our website.

Nonetheless, no communication via the Internet can ever be 100% secure. Accordingly, you are advised to use caution and discretion when determining what personal information to disclose to us via the site. If you have any questions about security on our site, contact us.

Modifications to this policy may occur in the future. We will reflect those changes in this statement and update the policy as needed.

## **Last Updated: May 24, 2018**
